I had a mucus
can't take the trash yeah sure sure
you know I do wonder if I logged in if
it would be better
yeah I think I'm gonna stray more but
this dream is gonna be a whole lot more
chill and yesterday's dream we'll see if
you really like it
my mother sent me an article this
morning about masks and the article is
totally complete trash and you know what
I regret talking about masks even this
stuff even this like anti Google the
problem with even talking about it
it is it attracts idiots whenever
whatever this is a good article for
everybody to read and this is this is
really how how people view it politics
is an extension of war by other means
arguments or soldiers once you know
which side you're on you must support
all arguments of that side and attack
all arguments that appear to favor the
enemy side otherwise it's like stabbing
your soldiers in the back providing aid
and comfort to the enemy people who
would be level-headed about
even-handedly weighing all sides of an
issue in their professional life as
scientists suddenly turn into slogan
chanting zombies when there's a blue or
green position on an issue
right the general level of discourse
about this kind of stuff is so much
lower so that's why we're working on the
busy beaver problem today and I was like
should I stream this or should I not
stream this you know I regret doing any
streams that ever talk about anything
remotely controversial because honestly
the Internet's about to it's a bunch of
immature fucks I'm not talking
specifically about my audience but the
the internet for the most part is is is
is immature Fox and you know you guys
don't know how to handle like the
intellectual and I I do think I'll make
this one point I think it has to do I'm
so sad for the internet that we lost I'm
so sad for the Internet 20 years ago on
the internet but I grew up with where it
wasn't like this and I do think it was
because well the people on the internet
were more mature and say
do some quick intro the busy beaver game
consists of designing a halting binary
alphabet Turing machine so not all
Turing machines halts on fall and some
don't
you can't know which ones you can know
for some to prove that a halting tired
Machine halts you can just run it and
figure out until it halts to prove a non
halting Turing machine does not halt
there's a few ways to do this so the
easiest way is if you get a cycle so you
can think of a Sigma you know Sigma
lowercase Sigma but now turn it around
right if your turn tiring tiring tiring
time you go on a turn loop and then you
reach a state that you've been in before
let's say at state 100 is a repeat of
state 30 well the same thing is gonna
happen again at state 170 you're gonna
get a repeat of state 100 which is state
30 so on and so forth so that has a I
mean y-intercept and slope aren't really
the right things but it has a intro of
of 30 and then like a step of 70 so what
is halting me
um so halting in a Turing machine is
usually just a state that States called
the halt state you can make more generic
statements like you can't prove of a
Turing machine ever gets into a certain
state so maybe a way to talk about this
is gonna be to look at do they have a
bunch of those nice old pictures here
they roll graphs
yeah yeah so this is like um this this
represents a time machine so if you're
in state a and you come upon a I don't
exactly there are there notations a
little bit different from mine so I
don't exactly understand it
um but Z is the halt state all right so
the Turing machine bounces around states
like a to be back to a to B to D that to
be back to a and then maybe it makes
this transition here over to Z I'll see
you that's what all that means
running my own private Wikipedia
instance it's never gonna my Wikipedia
imagine your computer hit you up and was
like yo could you give me $3 yo you got
$3 it's like it's like you know when I
go out on the street the homes people
give me $3 I go on Wikipedia give me $3
if it goes to see Ana terminates yeah
the rules for the two-state game are as
follows so it's it's a two-state wait no
not Tuesday so it's a binary alphabet so
it all it has is zeros and ones there's
two ways I've heard it talked about you
can say what is the machine that runs
for the longest without halting and then
what is the machine that writes the most
number of ones on the tape so a few cute
things it's really easy to show that the
the busy beaver function is non
computable I'm not sure this is the
proof that they're gonna go into but my
understanding of the simplest proof is
then well if you knew the busy beaver
number say for a 13 state Turing machine
and you had an arbitrary 13 state Turing
machine and you wanted to know whether
it was going to halt or not well you
could just simulate it for the busy
beaver functions number of steps and
then if it didn't halt it'll never halt
right busy beavers are totally and
completely useless and if you're looking
for useful shit fuck off from now on
this dream is a useless stream that
talks about nothing controversial except
for finite ism
this is this was a really cool super
impress when I saw this
you know you gotta be you gotta be
careful what links you click these days
this is see I want now I know Scott
Aaronson
let's try Scott Aaronson blog this I
want that I want no I want the blog post
turn machine DF independence ah yes
so
this is a really cool theory about so
the busy beaver number is theoretically
incomputable all right like you can't
there's no function that's going to
return the busy beaver for n but it
seems like we can get some of them right
we know the the number 4 2 3 & 4 what
we're gonna work on today is the number
4 5 which the number 4 5 we have a good
lower bound on it's easy to get a lower
bound if you as soon as you find the
machine with that number of states that
halts either after running for this many
steps or printing this many ones you
have a lower bound and if we happen to
magically find one that runs four more
steps or prints more ones we can update
these numbers but I don't think that
we're going to so this is talking about
the busy beaver number from the other
bound which says that the what busy
beaver number can't we compute and
there's some things in
yeah it follows as an immediate
consequence of goggles and completeness
care that there's some computer program
of some length
that eludes the power of ordinary
mathematics to prove what it does
yeah so that's it this is this is a cute
simple one enumerate all the possible
consequences of the CFC axioms you can
enumerate those that said axioms you can
apply them
I mean halt if it ever found a
contradiction assuming ZFC is consistent
this program must run forever but then
again assuming it's consistent it can't
prove that the program runs forever
since if it did that would prove with no
consistency thereby violating the second
it completes there so if you could
encode that axiom enumerator in a Turing
machine figure out how many states that
Turing machine has you know that busy
beaver number is is in computable you
can't know this this is a program in
math that you can prove that you can
never prove and as as fun little asides
they also made a 48 88 state Turing
machine that halts if there's a counter
example to Goldbach's conjecture
you all know Goldbach's conjecture
Globox conjecture says every number is
the sum of two primes except two I think
that's right I'm not going to fix it up
with something else
yeah every every integer great ever even
integer greater than 2 can be expressed
as two primes you take four it's two
plus two if you take six is b + 3 8 is 3
+ 5 so in sum and a 53 72 state machine
that halts if and only if there's a
counter example to the Riemann
hypothesis the Riemann hypothesis
explanation is too short to fit in this
stream but it says some weird stuff
about Zeta functions all that stuff and
someone just has to do with primes that
I read this proof out of this book yeah
no no I think yeah it's the same guy
I think I think I think this was the
book I read or maybe it was a it went
into trying to explain the Riemann
hypothesis and I really tried to go
through it and I would still love to sit
down with someone who can actually
explain to me what the Riemann
hypothesis is in a way that I understand
so this was this was done two years ago
they were so cool like I could have done
it you know so that's just it gives you
hope that math is accessible to - to
hackers because it's it certain it's
it's real it's real hacker stuff let's
let's get his name right Adam I'm not
even gonna try out the last name but he
wrote basically a Turing machine
compiler that makes small Turing
machines or this laconic that's a cute
language
and then this language compiles to small
towering machines
it has like an unpacker it's like
writing on a grating shellcode
so let's work through this paper um well
so here's my notes they're public as
part of the twitch cock repository on
github so if you're not evilly talking
about the five-state char machine you're
talking about how many well let's go
through what there
this is the notation that's being used
on this scale at page this pages from
2003 and let's look into who this guy is
he seemed she seemed to come pretty
close to to proving it and this was 2003
so I don't really know why he gave up
the codes in Pascal
and there's a yahoo email I mean I guess
that's what you had in 2003
do some anonymous person came just did
this so this is the notation that he
uses to represent the programs the
Turing machine programs the state is
imply the state is implied so this is
for state this is like a 0 a 1 meaning
it's a if you're in state a and 0 if
what you read on the tape is a 0 so then
this says transition to state C right a
0 to the tape and then move the tape
head left so naively not worrying at all
about D duping we say that there are six
states one of the states is those 5 plus
1 States because one of the states is a
halt state so you have 5 the halt state
once you enter the whole state you never
leave the whole state just spends a
little bit see if 5 plus 1 states 6 2
possible or I guess oh no no never mind
this is the 5 plus 1 States right here
so that's 6 6 possible values for this 2
possible values for this and two
possible values for this 6 times 2 times
2 is 24 there are 10 labels 24 to the 10
is 60 feet trillion so we have 63
trillion possible machines in which to
find our busy beaver
so usually whenever you're dealing with
searching in a set like this the first
thing you want to say is how many of
these machines are isomorphic how many
of these machines have the same behavior
like prove the same behavior so for
example one trivial way we can talk
about some some symmetries one symmetry
is the symmetry of the names of the
states so if I rename all the states to
other things with the exception of the
halt state because the whole state is
special because you halt and with the
exception of the a state because I
believe you start in the a state
then yeah there's there's still a lot of
degrees of freedom there which I can get
identical machines also left and right
the tape of the Turing machine is
completely symmetric so if I switch all
the left's two rights and all the rights
to left's it should do the same ones and
zeros would be symmetric work the goal
oh actually that's not true the Turing
machine starts with zeros so one's the
zeros are not symmetric so this is a
paper generating candidate busy beaver
machines or how to build the zany zoo so
if we can come up with a procedure that
allows us to generate candidates now
there's like words for this was my lack
of but if you have a function where
ideally I'd like a function where I can
say okay give me the 17,000,000
candidate and it will return me
something I don't need to iterate
through them I have a explicit formula
so let's read this paper I was sitting I
was looking at this paper this morning
and I realized something kind of sad too
as the internet reduces in content you
guys watch how I use the Internet you
watch how I highlight quickly and like
jump around and you kind of have to
because there's really very little
information in most web pages but this
is kind of breaking my brain for the
ability to sit and read something that's
very informational e dense I remember
getting a copy of critique of pure
reason and
I couldn't get past the first two pages
Tibor I know introduce the busy beaver
problem is an example of an on
computable function surprisingly simple
definition to find the largest number of
non blank characters that is output by a
terminating tire machine commencing on
the blink tank machine must be of no
more than a given size so that one can
define a function mapping the size of
the machine to the maximum size the
output produced
besides the Apple can be surprisingly
large for example there's a machine with
six states that terminates after the
beautiful thing about about the five
state busy beaver is the numbers
believed to be like 47 billion and 47
million we can write a Python ten to the
thirty six thousand yeah yeah that's
gonna require it's gonna require a lot
of speed-up tricks you don't you can't
actually simulate every step of that but
you can talk about its behavior what
it's going to do
principle this problem could be solved
by cleverly composing them particularly
machinery given size and proving that
it's maximum how do you prove that its
maximal without showing that all the
other ones are in practice solving
problem means analyzing all the machines
have given size and determining the
maximal one the evidence for maximality
such machines would be available mostly
he's complaining about the three and
four state machines not being
rigorously done
systematic analysis for the three-state
- symbol okay so obviously a program
should able to analyze all the 40
machines which were then analyzed by
hand they provided a description of
their method and a specification of the
40 machines but details are not provided
to reproduce what was done which is
interesting is I mean this is the same
approach taken by mr. skeleton so this
is the BB provers open source we can we
can run
after getting Pascal to compile you can
see it going through machines um no one
problem
we've potentially doing this one problem
with potentially doing this for five and
why perhaps it hasn't been done is you
may end up with the Collatz conjecture
we're gonna use my local instance of
Wikipedia for this because fuck the
internet the Collatz conjecture is it is
a conjecture mathematics that's concerns
a sequence to find a small start with
any positive integer and then each term
is obtained from the previous term as
follows if the previous term is even the
next term is one-half the previous term
if the previous term is odd the next
term is three times the previous term
plus one the conjecture is that no
matter that what value of n the sequence
will always reach one does the Collatz
sequence eventually reach one for all
positive integer initial values okay so
let's let's let's try one I'll write it
out so we're gonna start with six you
get to 3 right 3 times 3 plus 1 is 10
get to 5 that gets us to 16 alright
because 5 times 3 is 15 plus 1 16
divided by 2 because it's even as a 4 2
and then 1
so 6 works is that true for all numbers
now the problem with the Collatz
conjecture is the procedure is very very
simple yet there's no proof for this yet
so if we can show I don't think that
would be a really cool mathematical
result as well we could show well yeah I
mean that's the old all that sealed was
Hilbert was like some some mathematician
was criticizing Hilbert for his like
it's like Hilbert's list of unsolved
problems well anyone could write a list
of unsolvable problems it's so easy I
told her it's like okay give me give me
three and the mathematician couldn't
even come up with one because it's
really hard it's really hard to find
problems that are are hard to to say or
not busy beaver is an interesting place
to potentially look for these right
you'll have to translate you'll have to
translate this into a problem that
people can care about and demonstrate to
followers in Python because math math
seductive math is more likely to be
solved you imagine arresting he'll go
yeah so you got distracted we'll go back
to the paper
but analyze all before your machines
which it now is by hand provided
analysis of the four state to symbol
machines which also used programs to
reduce the unknown cases to to 1882 both
the times these remaining machines would
determine not to terminate due to the
human analysis well this is interesting
so this is basically saying that the
proofs for three and four aren't even
very good we just kind of came to accept
them and the five one is probably
correct as well but we live in an era
where we expect more rigor from anything
that looks consoling we do you
oh cool they actually said exactly what
I said anyone making a statement should
provide a substantially higher level of
computational evidence of course we will
do this all open source if we have any
luck I was one of the what what of one
of the things that I've never really
posted about anyway that I put a
surprising amount of my life into was
trying to find a collision in sha-1 it's
been done it's been done by the leader
in the space I read all his papers and
tried to implement them my
implementations whenever as good as his
but I wanted to use all I tried using
Sat solvers against it I still like this
code somewhere I have a Sat solver which
can find like 40 step collisions in
sha-1 but I couldn't get it sat really
interests me as well maybe well did we
do a stream that well he wrote us a
flower
maybe we tried we didn't actually get
through it because you know part of the
reason I was able to do twitch slam so
well is because I spent six months
before that like studying slam deeply
studying slam we have an internal slam
at comma so when it comes to writing a
toy one fort which I could do it very
well and twitch slam looks impressive
but what you don't see is all the work
that goes into it so if I do a Sat
solver stream you have to work in right
you know in some ways I have an
expectation for wanting this stream to
be high quality but I don't put much
effort into it so that's kind of on me
like if I want my stream to look like
shit talking our I prepare for this
dream like it should talking out you
know use a little bit more self-control
prep for and share the topping in
discord we don't have a discord I wish
we had nice tools
I wish we had tools which could build
nice communities part of it so part of
it I don't mean to just attack people
and say people have done a bad job at
this because like a lot of people it's
very hard it's it's not an easy problem
the only people who I would really
attack or people who I think are doing
it in bad faith in the early days of the
internet PHP BB MediaWiki these these
projects were not written in bad faith
Facebook wasn't written in bad faith it
changed over time
oh yeah so I mean if we could have a
nice community where you keep out really
all the toxicity then we can have a nice
discord where we could study and prepare
this is part of the reason I want to
make the college I think maybe it's a
fundamental problem with the internet
maybe it's a fundamental problem that
when you give people anonymity and weak
identity
you get toxicity and psychopathic
behavior
you get no no no person in real life
would treat you like a SEO medium post
would that only expects to ever have 30
seconds of your attention I mean sure
you know a beggar would at least at
least beggars I can respect more because
beggars is putting their their body in
front of me hey if you make me drive by
SEO content its you put nothing
they don't get flame yeah
if everybody stopped clicking those
links and everybody stop giving beggars
money it would all right that's the
truth about solving a lot of problems
too the coordination is hard but solving
the busy
you see that's something we can do and
it's beautiful because it's meaningless
like the people who appreciate it I
think I've talked about this before in
order to appreciate
I think III vacillate and I make dreams
like this sometimes where I get fed up
but the other stuff and it goes in Siple
reminder to future me when you feel the
other way watch this stream maybe it'll
work
Davis girl once she lived a nice text
message on the machine very nice that's
just how she was sad about how she acted
this way and so forth and then you know
she's acting that way again and I played
it the text message it didn't work maybe
maybe there's not really hope oh you
can't do it do you maybe all choose just
not dynamic
papers hilarious for picking on mediocre
research and rinse and repeat articles
in ml yeah but is that paper any better
is that paper any better
I don't like the libs either but owning
libs is not I don't like that either
let's build better systems
don't look at the comments they're a
distraction all right
there are over N to the N machines of
size n stroke that's you had an end on
both sides of the video yeah it's it's
actually it's yeah 4 into the two and no
not exactly because assaulting for n
plus one based to it Big O notation is
correct
second the process for generating
machines needs to be carefully
considered and based on sound principles
rather than simply generating all
machines of a given size oh well I mean
that's true too if you have machines
that have no connections between if some
states are entirely disconnected or if
you have Islands this is effectively
machine of size 3 rather than the size 5
so tremendous exclusion to be avoided if
possible thirdly in order to determine
the busy beaver function when you only
to analyze the execution of these
machines on a single input that means we
kept engine takes place properties the
intermissions the classic way to address
these issues and to intermingle the
generation of the machines with their
execution I've seen this so I actually
implemented this basically the trick is
whenever you can do a state transition
do it you'll and do both you'll find the
code I have the code for this yeah yeah
tnf Oh beautiful
so if we run TNF I think this is gonna
get alright yeah this is all the
possible machines with three states and
I think it eventually gives us the right
answer
yeah so if you're interested entry
normal form it's already implemented in
the twitch concrete box
get a parsley define machine in the
blanket Bunch on I like your transition
it was an appropriate additional one its
allocated there's only one of these
checks so it does it it does it
dynamically but this doesn't have that
property that I want I don't want a
recursive definition I want a the word
that comes to my mind is imperative but
that's not right
the TNF approach makes it attractive
resisting the process generate and
analyze machines rather than separating
the two is discussed above oh actually I
remember also if you want to run this
shit mad fast yeah pi PI
so prints the machine prints whether the
Machine bolts or not it doesn't I'm
gonna get fault
I think believe the other machines in
like Joe Ron oh this is wrong I have I
have my time machine runner over here
you know and M s equals 100 means that
I'll run it for 100 steps that's why I'm
getting all those 101 ok busy or - Wow I
even - takes a long time
so 4 - we got 6 and for all ass all
signal
Eggman
so that's the count and that's the
number so six and four I would expect to
find as the the numbers for yeah so six
and four
how's it for two states so that's my
middle of three normal form program
so yes this is all implemented
our intention is to provide a data set
consisting of all machines which need to
be considered for the busy beaver
problem of a given size so this the
scalloped edge estimates that Phoebe
proved our searches a hundred and fifty
million machines so 150 million actually
if the way that we have to do it is by
generating a big table that's okay
like we can you can turn a recursive
function into a function where I can do
lookups by making a table
somebody's talking about the importance
of separating it into the generation one
child proach will suffice the complete
analysis procedure which is known in
advance to be capable of analyzing
omissions of interest is available this
is generally unrealistic in practice and
so it seems necessary to have an
incremental development cycle involving
testily and partially developed
technique on a class of machines our
intention is to provide a data set
consisting of all machines which need to
be considered for the busy beaver
problem of a given size minimize the
size of the set when possible
it's even more important to ensure we
didn't exclude anything
this means we generally cannot reduce
the number of irrelevant machines
retained for analysis to zero for sure
it's irrelevant improving its relative
right because you do actually
technically need a proof for the full
combinatorics trillions and so you do
actually need a proof for the the dirty
there's sixty three trillion basically
yeah what you would need to show is you
need to show a procedure that can
canonicalize any machine so if we want
like a certain ordering yeah right 36
trillion is a 10 to the 16 that's that's
large 62 Chile I think today yeah
actually it's almost 10 to 17 so that's
that's that's beyond what we're gonna
run today what is when is 10 to the 17
analog I always like thinking in twos
log to see the news articles 56
say to 30 cents so yeah I mean can you
do to the 56 yeah but most try to find a
better way to I mean so so like what you
could do with two to the 56 is you could
say you could enumerate everyone and
then come up with just little little
like like a proof system to kind of say
this one's equivalent to this one it's
already on the list this one's
equivalent to this one it's already on
the last right I like writing things
that look like that more on section 2 we
discussed related work and in section 3
we discuss preliminaries or their quote
is available to which I just write a
dataset of all the machines which needs
to be considered clearly it's important
to minimize this all she's irrelevant
you're gonna have some that are stupid
but in there for this reason we need to
investigate formal results which
establish the correctness of constraints
of the type of machines that need to be
generated in order to solve a busy
beaver related problems we define what
is meant by being relevant to the busy
beaver problem and give results were to
establish a shannon ish eliminating
certain cases yeah we provide a
procedure for generating machines code
and the results are available in the
author's website okay that's I think I
think we understand now what it does
let's take a look
by the way it's more important now than
ever to save archive.org I find myself
using it more and more
25 petabytes for reference comma has to
pay two bytes
oh the observant honor let's learn about
the observant daughter
yeah that's to my Zotero
why are you waving
you know
so here I think
we don't they posting all numbers
there's certainly numbers we could write
it's just download this
Wow good thing that's on archive.org
I'll add it to money I don't think don't
mind
turning pearl god
there's no license
the good news is I'm looking at this I'd
like to aside from this one uses pearl
and this one uses Pascal like aside from
the weird choices of languages it seems
like this stuff's like written by
hackers
okay
so
and I would assume that this six of
states and the two is symbols and it's
interesting that yeah they've gotten it
a hundred and two million
well okay so to get an idea of the size
of the compute where si oh cool it's a
lookalike think about we can we can well
I was doing the file see if we can
understand their format dude Wow Wow
they saved in a hundred Meg's if file oh
that was so polite of them oh I love the
Internet Archive donate to the Internet
Archive
they've never harassed me for donation
see that's why I don't know yeah
and with the dying of the internet you
know
cybersecurity is a racket now I'm
donating through the cloud
I'm just going to use their park own
homes it take
it's not pearl what is PL prologue is it
prologue it's pro the gates prologue the
good news is somebody used prologue for
merge sort
so I know I'm right this metal fun
project or it just look like pearls
yeah 105 extension I do think this
actually isn't prologue
see if it looks like prologue looks like
fun
sniffle
sorry
there see
No
hmm
- teammate
I'm going procedure main oh I get it so
you can like swipe all G generate and
then when I run that I think I'd like
imports
create machines States symbols appointed
errors style of types - yes
we've ders
yeah
you know it would be nice if they had a
example yeah here we go
odors is directions not a directory Oh
top
Wow here we go
abs Tianna those normal things
unknown procedure directory
let's compile the top
not with GMA g-man was a mistake
yes
that whim would not create correct goal
so the problem was actually that I
didn't the problem wasn't generate fun
was that I didn't link it to whatever
other bullshit I needed directory
that way no Gmail
director EC : / busy beaver data raw
busy beaver 5 to 2 does not exist
somebody's of Windows
yeah here we go directory for import
directory where results camera one on
raw and they want a results
a machinist Oh
unknown procedure bound sex probably
jail
complained about a lot of stuff
unknown procedural fault trams yeah we
tried the my download finish
our file
you're appalled
[Music]
great
okay um we could try to get this code to
run but then it still involves trusting
so this is the first step in our in our
step here we have our attack steps here
so we can re implement whatever there
are search procedure is and hopefully we
get the same number of machines that
would be that would be very satisfying
if we could if we could finish step one
on part on this part one extreme I don't
think it's
but that's probably too ambitious for
the first part in-stream because math is
really slow
yeah it's prologue but you see the white
coated windows path
okay so here's kind of what I'm thinking
we probably could have recovered that
but like what would have we really ended
up with
here's kind of what I'm thinking me
reading this paper on streams not that
interesting so tonight my homework and
your homework is to read this paper so
this paper is called generating canopy's
fever machines or how to build the same
zoom The Associated code is now in my
github and tomorrow we're going to
reimplemented and that's going to be
step one we're gonna re-implemented on
I'll be on stream probably tomorrow
around the same time I can't link the
comments or online or on my phone but I
think this is kind of gonna be the new
the new style for a bit yeah we have a
stream schedule right pretty hardcore if
you like this stuff please subscribe I'm
gonna look at my twitch monies and if
I've been making a lot of twitch monies
I'm more excited to do this if I've been
making less twitch monies I'm less
excited to do this and I'm never doing
another coronavirus stream you know back
in the day you could talk about
coronavirus and then idiots took over
the discourse I didn't realize I didn't
realize how it changed I thought you
could
yeah I thought I thought over over two
months it seems like anyone who was who
was interested in I saw a joke and the
joke was like the guy goes up to a dr.
zeig a doctor when his coronavirus gonna
be over and the doctor said but he
asking me for ask a politician colory
first well thank you for subscribing
mooch was taken whoosh whoosh was taken
Christian James thank you for
subscribing only people who passed the
test should be allowed in the stream
yeah we can I can run that over with my
content team and my production manager
away I don't have any of that shit right
oh good yeah my notebooks is a good repo
that code is pretty clean get your VIP
star subscribe today subscribe now oh
actually the other thing that I was
thinking about is the end of these
things always ends up being a QA is
there like a I want kind of like a
reddit style for the questions you know
I want I want like instead of just I
could just make a reddit yeah I like
reddit thought private reddit instance
no no I don't want there to be the
reason I don't want there to be a reddit
is I don't want there to be a persistent
place no rats are right but I don't want
there to be for the same reason that
there's no discord and I'll be
infuriated if anybody makes one is the
problem with a persistent place is that
place is going to be taken over by it by
the psychopaths right the if you stand
up something quickly everyone is there
if no it's just like oh we just showed
up that the the minds of those kind of
people haven't yet figured out how to
exploit yet kind of the Janus I'm always
talking about this Oh Janice yeah
just turn it into sub only and let
people ask questions at the end oh yeah
that's a good point
yeah all right let's go solve only
yeah well we'll answer a few questions
but only for subscribers it's a good
point that's a good point they're
probably better people I mean any Q&A
for slobs
she'd be nice to have like a nice list
of questions you know like curated you
guys can vote a relatively short stream
today but we're gonna try to turn us
into as an a stream how should someone
who never coded start learning to code
see if you weren't a sob I brush away
that question real fast but actually you
know what's a more interesting question
would you fuck a polar bear and no I
wouldn't I mean will you fucking normal
bear like let's start there and then
like would you fuck a dog right like you
know where does it where does it stop
man you know where it stops animals
does it bother you that Peter teal is so
popular in start-up culture I didn't
even know that was true
and by the way how do I learn to code
question actually is a worse question
than would you fuck a polar bear and
that says a lot for that question
the problem with making a discord for
people who pass a test is who's gonna
maintain the test what's gonna happen
when somebody passes around the guide to
pass the test and the thing you gotta
moderation as a continual process I
don't get paid enough for it
object-oriented programming become the
standard as opposed to functional
because it takes forever to do anything
in Haskell lambda man yeah it just takes
long to code in the house
it's gonna be the same few questions
every time yeah I mean that that's the
nice thing about the you or the hype
train I'd rather be remembered for my
something I haven't done yet it might be
remember for that shit you'll see what
I'll remember for
if I can pull the parity to cover this
funny yeah just pay someone to maintain
the test for you see you know a lot of
people tell me this kind of stuff like
if I understand you know you're rich you
just pay other people to do stuff for
you
yeah well paying other people to do
stuff for you isn't that easy because
you run into the same problem of well
who's confident how do I judge their
competence do have to interview them
right and eventually yeah you could
probably build like a structure that's
capable of doing this how many high as
15 people I still have to deal with a
lot of this stuff hopefully last night
we're trying to transition away from it
but it took five years and 15 people is
backprop gonna be obsolete in 20 years
throwback problem I think backdrops
gonna continue for a long time I have
yet to see the brain doesn't use
backdrop at least not the same way
there's no way the brain is background
if you like ten layers
so why is there a need to create an
elite private community wouldn't it be
simply easier to set up some simple chat
rules and have mods enforce it you can't
do this because the problem isn't
moderating obvious spam the problem is
somebody's producing content that
doesn't violate any of the rules but
it's really low-quality
it's a quality problem not a rules
violation problem and you can't you can
have a rule that says for example you
know no racist comments and they're easy
to moderate but having a rule that says
no low-quality comments will that's
subject
can we feed gbg3 a lot of code and get
it to code Jen so I had this like idea
for backspace and I kind of wanted to do
this I think what you can get with them
as you can build pretty good linkers you
can find bugs by finding code that's low
but people don't when people if you
watch me code I don't start at the top
and slowly go down to the bottom unless
you have a system that's capable of like
jumping around and editing I don't think
it can code it racism is subjective as
well today so even even a simple rule
like that right so this this rule thing
is completely impossible low-quality
content and Chad is just a part of the
twitch chat experience yeah that
how do we attack
low quality stuff period in in the real
world there is kind of a social pressure
against it right because people have
like one identity nobody wants to start
being known as oh this is the guy who
just you know post trash I mean this is
probably what I'm gonna do next or I
know math is a fun hobby but I'm never
gonna I'm never gonna gonna make it as a
as a mathematician it's unclear that's
maybe when you first read less wrong you
think about recursive self-improvement a
you think that math is what's gonna save
the world and the more I've grown off I
realized that politics is gonna save the
world
you've just never been exposed to
anything that looks remotely like their
politics like most math is good most
papers that are published especially in
in weird parts of math are good because
who cares except people who are really
who really work hard and care there's no
you don't get any power in exchange for
these things so it only attracts the
right kind of people um
politics always attracts the worst kind
of people so you've never seen good
politics
what does good moderation look like I
think a lot of the Internet is is
struggling with this now
yeah I wonder
this is this is like what I want to
build the college all right I think by
having a physical space where there is a
barrier to entry that you actually have
to show up and and in order to place
your body there already will cut down
maybe this is why yeah online learning
and online communities can't happen
you're you're you're better there well
I'm not saying they can't happen but
until we solve this problem they'll
never be as good as real-life
communities can be
so I mean even that comment I guess
Trump is not a good example for good
politics that's not what politics is
if the you hear the word politics and
the first thing you think is Trump
you're that's like hearing the word math
and the first thing you you know you you
think man that's not it's not a good
analogy politics is the way to construct
systems that maybe prevent the tragedy
of the Commons if you think about our
key is the absence of politics you don't
know one lesson live in an organic is a
terrible place to live politics is what
comes in to replace anarchy
marriage an insight on mark says the key
to political change isn't changing the
minds of the masses but changing the
minds attention hundred bright people
for a given age I think that's right the
masses is down stood the belief in the
politics the art yoga here the art or
science of government or governing let's
say forget the especially let's just
leave it at that
the art or science of government of
governing and that's exactly what you're
asking the Janney's that's what they're
doing
right that's what moderation is that's
what building a good community is
and our yeah anarchy which which like
white or black is like the absence of
color anarchy is the absence of politics
I mean it's not really actually you are
you're governed then just by the law of
nature is it is so completely might
makes right
you know but me if politics is not the
way forward and maybe we use another
word for it because that word is so is
so tinged with with with crap um we need
a Bitcoin for society that's a good
comment I'm not sure I'm not sure how
literally you meant that if you mean it
literally as in we just pay society with
Bitcoin and everything will be fine
that's not true but the the
formalization of the system in Bitcoin
if you could figure out how to do that
for moderation
yeah a system that relies on everybody
becoming enlightened I don't see I don't
see working so well this yeah you want
to build a system that has the right
sort of you want to build a system that
rewards quality and punishes lack of
quality let's just say your social
network right I mean social networks
what are what are the people its
governance in a social network whatever
your policies are if you could figure
out how to build a social network that
rewards quality and punishes lack of
quality you'd end up with the most
incredible social networks so quickly
the problem is what are the experts
right so there's two ways to avoid
explains and this is true in in security
as well so one way to avoid exploits is
to build something that is so incredibly
secure the other way to avoid exploits
is to not have something worth taking so
these are actually that's all in the
same spectrum if you have a system that
costs $100 to attack but only has 20
dollars of value on it that system is
not going to be attacked but if you have
a system that has 100 that cost $1 to
attack but has you know a thousand
dollars of value on it then that system
is going to be attacked right I mean if
that cost can include everything that
cost can include we go risk and all that
so on and so forth so the reason math
seems to remain quality is that there is
nothing really a value to take math kind
of is its own reward
um well he of course that is that is the
ultimate the ultimate problem who
defines what is quality and what is not
is quality objective no it's not a just
it's it's well but even true there's not
no objectivity when it comes to people
there's certainly a some objectivity for
example there's no human that can run as
fast as a cheetah that's an objective
statement is true quality is truth yeah
again this suffers from this problem of
you can say a lot of meaningless true
stuff
one component of politics is influencing
other towards your ideas and no not
everybody's into politics I really I I
hate the idea but what else do you do
when you realize that's if I could save
the world through skateboarding I'd be a
pro skateboarder save the world through
math I'd be a mathematician but who's
gonna end the world with humans
see but okay a statement like that means
you don't understand what I mean when I
say politics a statement like the media
influences more people than the politics
what's the difference all of that falls
under an umbrella of like governments
the one who does a lot of interesting
stuff in crypto about this crypto people
I find just using that word governance I
realized that crypto people talk about
this all the time and they talk yeah but
maybe this is kind of a solution
too bad people thought they were there
was power there and ruined Krypton you
have to figure out the humans are
fundamentally economic creatures you
have to figure out how to make sure
incentives are aligned for everybody to
produce quality the initial hope of
social media was the users would
regulate content quality by likes and
upvotes yeah I guess I think is that
that naive I don't think so I mean 10
years ago I don't think that was naive I
don't know maybe 10 but I don't know 20
years ago yeah I don't think it was
naive at all
well everyone wants a good tailor
the problem is that the good part and
dictatorship suffers from sets of
problems that democracy campus I mean
there are some problems that are better
handled indicator ships though some
problems that have better handled in
democracies but this isn't even I'm
talking more about a new politics I'm
not talking about oh if only we'd elect
the Green Party or the blue party or the
red party know the system the substrate
on which they're playing is
fundamentally broken yeah the good
dictatorship that kid that takes over I
mean that's not the classic problem
Plato would have hated like some up
close something something that I really
want to
what Oh I'm streaming but that died yeah
who knows whatever Plato's Academy
apparently like Pythagoras found like
five hundred people who want to learn
math well I put them up in a building
and called it like yeah the Pythagorean
forget what he called it but that kind
of stuff okay we could do that again
today here's the thing about science do
you believe inside so you don't have to
believe in science people who you know
don't believe in nuclear physics still
get blown up by the bomb
to Sparta of engineering yeah it's not a
bad idea right you know I had to agree I
got it I gotta read more that stuff oh I
wish I wish I could I wish I could focus
more and read more stuff like that
maybe connect he's riding our brands
with everyone saying about these days
do you think the world will always be
full of inequalities I think it's a
stupid thing to focus on I think it's
bad we should focus on the sum sum of
all people the world is not a zero-sum
game
I'm not trying to change the society I'm
whoa whoa not that guy
I'm not trying to change the society
that's not at all what my ambitions are
I'm trying to build a new place that is
very high quality
I started combi with the mission of
changing the culture sure it's working
for you well am I gonna get to clown the
automaker's am I gonna get to finally
laugh at like you know forwards backward
ways of doing things
yeah kind of looks like it but I didn't
win I didn't win in the same way
theranos didn't lose for the right
reasons right like that they won't learn
the lesson so there's no point changing
a society is stupid how do we build a
new society that's good should I ban bra
flourishes trumped I don't care if
you're the subscriber
what is a good politician it's not even
why are there people was a people why
they're people
I want systems
bias.com is quality
it feels good to be a sub yeah it does
feel good to be yourself but no one sub
should know how good it feels
biased
all right that's today's QA
thank you all for watching everybody
please read the paper and tomorrow we're
going to construct the zany zoo in
Python which will complete step one of
our attack thank you all for watching I
hope the world becomes a better place
I'm training to elbow
the cancer will